Guide to Houston area land records for the Little, Dickson and Pastoriza additions, 1877-1935
Woodson Research Center
Houston area land records for the Little, Dickson and Pastoriza additions
1877-1935
Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University, Houston, TX
0.25 linear feet
This collection consists of 11 abstracts of title and one warranty deed for property in the city of Houston and Harris County, filed from 1877 to 1935.
MS 432
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 11 abstracts of title and one warranty deed for property in the city of Houston and Harris County, filed from 1877 to 1935. The first series deals with property in the R.J. Little Addition, north side of Buffalo Bayou, and the John Dickinson Addition, north side of Buffalo Bayou. The warranty deed was for property belonging to Martha J. Blalock. The second series of property was part of the Pastoriza Addition, southside of Buffalo Bayou from the Luke Moore League (survey).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one box with each of the two series consisting of items donated by the individual whose name is included in the series title where the item is located.
Series I. Gift of Mrs. Clifton N. Hancock; property North of Buffalo Bayou, 1902-1910.
Series II. Gift of Mrs. Ida Siegel; property south of Buffalo Bayou. 1877-1935, n.d.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Hancock, Clifton N., Mrs. -- donor.; Siegel, Ida -- donor.
Places
Harris County (Tex.) - land development.; Houston (Tex.) - land development.
Subjects:
Land Records; Abstract Records
Acquisition Information
The first series of three abstracts and one deed was given to the Woodson by Mrs. Clifton N. Hancock in December 1987. The second series was given by Mrs. Ida Siegel in January 1987.
Accruals
No future additions are expected for this material.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Gift of Mrs. Clifton N. Hancock, 1902-1910.
  Containing abstracts of title for property north of Buffalo bayou, and a warranty deed for property belonging to Martha J. Blalaock, 1902-1910.
  - Abstract of Title no. 874. For "Lots 7 8 in block 27 of J.R. Little addition to the city of Houston, on the north side of Buffalo Bayou.", Filed in 1902; 1.
  - Abstract of Title no. 1133. For "Lot 7 Block 27 Little addition to the city of Houston, Harris County, Texas.", Filed in 1909; 2.
  - Abstract of Title no. 1133. For "Lot number 7, block number 27 in the John Dickinson Addition, Norht side of Buffalo Bayou.", Filed in 1910; 3.
  - General Warranty Deed. For "lot 7 in block 27 in the John Dickinson Addition to the City of Houston, Texas, or north side of Buffalo Bayou." To Martha Blalock, Filed in 1909; 4.
- Series II: Gift of Mrs. Ida Siegel
  Containing abstracts of title for property south of Buffalo Bayou. 1877-1935, n.d.
  - Supplemental Abstract of Title. For "15.53 acres out of the Southern portion of the East half of Lot 1 of the West half of the Luke Moore League, ... Harris County, Texas.", Filed in 1908; 5.
  - Two copies of Supplemental Abstract of Title no. 4489. For "15.53 acres out of the Southern portion of hte East half of Lot 1 of the West half of hte Luke Moore League, in the City of Houston, as described in deed from T.W. Archer to J.J Pastoriza.", Filed in 1908; 6.
  - Two copies of Abstract of Title. For "32 and 1840/5640 acres of land out of Lot no. 1, of the west half of the Luke Moore League, Harris County, Texas, owned by W. J. Coulter and R.J. Thacker.", 7.
  - Abstract of Title no. 31948. For "Lot no. 12, block no. 5 of Pastoriza Addition to the City of Houston.", n.d. With copy of 1906 abstract attached.; 8.
  - Abstract of Title no. 31948. For "Lot no. 12, block no. 5 of Pastoriaza Addition to the City of Houston.", Filed in 1913; 9.
  - Abstract of Title no. 107/172. For "Lot 9 in block 1 and lot 11 in block 5 of the Pastoriza Addition to the City of Houston, on the South Side of Buffalo Bayou.", Filed in 1877; 10.
  - Abstract of Title no. 59561. For "Lot Number 12, in Block Number 5, J.J. Pastoriza Addition, an Addition of the City of Houston, on the South Side of Buffalo Bayou.", Filed in 1935; 11.
  - Abstract of Title no. 13101. For "Lots 2 and 9, block 1; Lot 11, block 5, Pastoriza Addition to the city of Houston.", Filed in 1915; 12.